Guide to the Norman Dorsen Papers TAM.251
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Correspondence.
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jan 1971 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Feb 1971 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Mar 1971 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Apr 1971 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Outgoing correspondence, May 1971 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jun 1971 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jul 1971 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Aug 1971 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Sep 1971 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Oct 1971 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Nov 1971 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Dec 1971 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jan 1972 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Feb 1972 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Mar 1972 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Apr 1972 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Outgoing correspondence, May 1972 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jun 1972 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jul 1972 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Aug 1972 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Sep 1972 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Oct 1972 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Nov 1972 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Dec 1972 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jan 1973 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Feb 1973 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Mar 1973 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Apr 1973 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Outgoing correspondence, May 1973 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jun 1973 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jul 1973 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Aug 1973 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Sep 1973 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Oct 1973 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Nov 1973 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Dec 1973 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jan 1974 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Feb 1974 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Mar 1974 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Apr 1974 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Outgoing correspondence, May 1974 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jun 1974 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jul 1974 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Aug 1974 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Aug 1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Sep 1976 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Oct 1976 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Nov 1976 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Dec 1976 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jan 1977 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Feb 1977 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Mar 1977 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Apr 1977 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Outgoing correspondence, May 1977 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jun 1977 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jul 1977 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Aug 1977 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Sep 1977 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Oct 1977 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Nov 1977 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Dec 1977 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jan 1978 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Feb 1978 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Mar 1978 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Apr 1978 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Outgoing correspondence, May 1978 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jun 1978 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jul 1978 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Aug 1978 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Sep 1978 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Oct 1978 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Nov 1978 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Dec 1978 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jan 1979 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Feb 1979 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Mar 1979 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Apr 1979 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Outgoing correspondence, May 1979 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jun 1979 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jul 1979 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Aug 1979 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Sep 1979 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Oct 1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Nov 1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Dec 1979 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jan 1980 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Feb 1980 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Mar 1980 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Apr 1980 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Outgoing correspondence, May 1980 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jun 1980 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jul 1980 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Aug 1980 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Sep 1980 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Oct 1980 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Nov 1980 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Dec 1980 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jan 1981 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Feb 1981 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Mar 1981 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Apr 1981 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Outgoing correspondence, May 1981 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jun 1981 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jul 1981 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Aug 1981 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Sep 1981 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Oct 1981 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Nov 1981 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Dec 1981 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jan 1982 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Feb 1982 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Mar 1982 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Apr 1982 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Outgoing correspondence, May 1982 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jun 1982 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jul 1982 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Aug 1982 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Sep 1982 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Oct 1982 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Nov 1982 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Dec 1982 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jul 1985 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Aug 1985 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Sep 1985 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Oct 1985 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Nov 1985 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Dec 1985 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jan 1986 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Feb 1986 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Mar 1986 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Apr 1986 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Outgoing correspondence, May 1986 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jun 1986 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jul 1986 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Aug 1986 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Sep 1986 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Oct 1986 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Nov 1986 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Dec 1986 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Jan 1987 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Feb 1987 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Mar 1987- Jun 1988 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    General note
    Includes one letter from U.S. Supreme Court Justice William J. Brennan and one letter from U.S. Supreme Court Justice John Harlan.
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    Includes one letter from U.S. Supreme Court Justice William J. Brennan and three letters from U.S. Supreme Court Justice John Harlan.
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    Includes two letters from U.S. Supreme Court Justice John Harlan.
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Includes one letter from U.S. Supreme Court Justice William J. Brennan.
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    Includes one letter from U.S. Supreme Court Justice Harry A. Blackmun.
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Includes two letters from U.S. Supreme Court Justice William J. Brennan.
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Includes one letter from U.S. Supreme Court Justice William J. Brennan and one letter from U.S. Supreme Court Justice Harry A. Blackmun.
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Includes three letters from U.S. Supreme Court Justice William J. Brennan and four letters from U.S. Supreme Court Justice Harry A. Blackmun.
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Includes two letters from U.S. Supreme Court Justice William J. Brennan and one letter from then U.S. Circuit Judge, future U.S. Supreme Court Justice Antonin Scalia.
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Includes two letters from U.S. Supreme Court Justice Harry A. Blackmun.
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Includes one letter from U.S. Supreme Court Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg.
  - Correspondence - Public, 1961-1963 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Public, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Public, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Public, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Public, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Public, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Public, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Public, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Public, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Public, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - Public, 1977-1986 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Series II: Writings, speeches, and public appearances.
  - Conferences - Antioch Conference on Civil Rights, Civil Liberties, and Poverty Law in the 1980s, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Conferences - Bonn Symposium on Constitutional Law, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Conferences - British Institute of Human Rights, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Conferences - British Institute of Human Rights - correspondence, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Conferences - British Institute of Human Rights - pamphlets, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Conferences - Buffalo Conference on the Future of the Bill of Rights, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Conferences - Civil Liberties in the Year 2001, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Conferences - Color Blind or Color Conscious, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Conferences - Conscription and Civil Liberties, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Conferences - Ditchley Foundations, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Conferences - Federal Bar Council, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Conferences - Federal judges, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Conferences - General, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Conferences - Georgia Constitution, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Conferences - International Conference on Abortion, Washington DC, 1967-1968 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Conferences - Judicial Conference of the Second Circuit, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Conferences - Law and National Security, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Conferences - Liberty Conference, Jul 1986 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Conferences - National Council for Civil Liberties (UK), Academic Freedom Conference, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Conferences - NYC Review Board, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Conferences - Professional Codes of Ethics, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Conferences - Public Administration Committee, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Conferences - Williamsburg - Religion and the State, Apr 1986 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Lectures - Baum Lecture, 1981-1986 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Includes one letter from U.S. Supreme Court Justice Stephen Breyer.
  - Lectures - Baum Lecture - administrative, 1981-1985 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Lectures - Cooley Lecture, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Lectures - Cooley Lecture at University of Michigan Law School and Blasi SALT Book, 1980-1984 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Includes one letter from U.S. Supreme Court Justice John Paul Stevens.
  - Lectures - Orgain and Handmaker Lectures, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Lectures - Orgain Lecture, 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Lectures - Orgain Lecture, 1969-1973 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Lectures - Orgain Lecture, 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Lectures - Orgain Lecture, 1969-1971 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Public appearances, 1967-1970 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Public appearances, 1961-1972 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Public appearances, 1964-1972 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Public appearances, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    Some papers damaged.
  - Public appearances, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Public appearances, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Public appearances, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Public appearances, 1975-1978 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Public appearances, American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Public appearances, Point Park College, Jun 1967 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Public appearances, Puerto Rico, Jan 1969 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Public appearances, Toronto, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Public statements, 1963-1968 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Public statements, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Public statements, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Public statements, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Public statements, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Public statements, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Public statements, 1974-1976 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Ripon College Honorary Degree Award (and public statement), 1980-1985 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Speeches - Albany speech to law review editors, Apr 1976 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Speeches - American Bar Association, Honolulu meeting, Aug 1967 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Speeches - Bicentennial speech - Separation of Powers & Federalism, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Speeches - Magna Carta celebration, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Testimony - National Commission on the Causes and Prevention of Violence -Task Force on Law and Law Enforcement, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Testimony - National Commission on the Causes and Prevention of Violence -Task Force on Law and Law Enforcement, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Testimony - National Commission on the Causes and Prevention of Violence -Task Force on Law and Law Enforcement, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Testimony - Product Liability Act, 1984-1986 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Testimony - Rockefeller Commission on CIA, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Testimony, Congressional - Abortion - Federal Court remedies, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Testimony, Congressional - Abortion - S.522 on Federal funding, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Testimony, Congressional - Amendment to Voting Rights Act, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Testimony, Congressional - Committee on Government Operations - Senator Ribicoff, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Testimony, Congressional - Constitutional Amendment on Religious Activities, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Testimony, Congressional - Equal Rights Amendment, 1970-1977 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Testimony, Congressional - Equal Rights Amendment, 1970-1972 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Testimony, Congressional - Equal Rights Amendment, 1970-1975 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Testimony, Congressional - Establishment Clause, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Testimony, Congressional - Executive Privilege / Arab boycott, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Testimony, Congressional - House Committee on Interstate and Foreign Commerce, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Testimony, Congressional - Letter to Subcommittee on Constitutional Rights on Wiretapping, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Testimony, Congressional - Muriel Cuban Detainees, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Testimony, Congressional - No Fault Insurance Act- Correspondence, Miscellaneous, 1973-1976 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    Includes one letter from U.S. Supreme Court Justice William J. Brennan and one letter from U.S. Supreme Court Justice Potter Stewart.
  - Testimony, Congressional - Office of Congressional Legal Counsel, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Testimony, Congressional - Select Committee on Intelligence - Congressman Otis G. Pike, 1974-1976 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Testimony, Congressional - Select Committee on Intelligence - Congressman Otis G. Pike, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Testimony, Congressional - Select Committee on Intelligence, Hearing on FBI and domestic intelligence - Senator Church, 1975-1976 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Testimony, Congressional - Subcommittee on Constitutional Rights, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Testimony, Congressional - Subcommittee on Intergovernmental Relations testimony - Senator Muskie Chairman, 1973-1975 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Writings - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU) Handbook Series - Inventory, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Writings - Albany speech to law review editors (Craft and Character in American Law and Law Reviews, draft article), 1976 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Writings - Civil Liberties in Conflict (Gostin), 1977-1988 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Writings - Democracy and the Rule of Law, 2000-2002 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Writings - Disorder in the Court - NYC Bar, 1971-1987 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Writings - Disorder in the Court - NYC Bar - Reviews and correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Writings - Emerson and Haber - 1977 Supplement, 1977-1978 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Writings - Emerson and Haber - 1981 Supplement to Volume II, 1980-1981 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Writings - Emerson and Haber - Business and royalties (fourth edition), 1972-1985 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Writings - Emerson and Haber - College Edition, 1967-1975 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Writings - Emerson and Haber - Comments on Volume I, Fourth edition, 1976-1978 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Writings - Emerson and Haber - Correspondence and miscellaneous, 1964-1966 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Writings - Emerson and Haber - Correspondence and miscellaneous, 1966-1976 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Writings - Emerson and Haber - Miscellaneous, 1975-1976 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Writings - Emerson and Haber - Permission Requests to Reprint Excerpts, 1968-1978 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Writings - Emerson and Haber - Permissions for Political and Civil Rights in the United States, Volume I, 1975-1979 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Writings - Emerson and Haber - Political and Civil Rights General Material / Outline, 1973-1975 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Writings - Emerson and Haber - Political and Civil Rights General Material / Outline, 1976-1977 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Writings - Emerson and Haber - Post-publication publicity and reviews, 1967-1978 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Writings - Emerson and Haber - Press, 1966-1967 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Writings - Emerson and Haber - Volume I - 1980 Supplement, 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Writings - Emerson and Haber - Volume I - Correspondence, 1975-1979 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Writings - Emerson and Haber - Volume I and Volume II and 1975 Supplement General, 1974-1980 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Writings - Emerson and Haber - Volume II, Fourth edition - Outline and Correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Writings - Emerson and Haber - Volume II, Fourth edition - Outline and Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Writings - Executive Privilege (Ohio State article), 1973 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Writings - Frontiers II (not written), 1976-1984 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Writings - Fundamentals of American Law, 1994-2002 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Writings - Israel, 1963-1974 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Writings - John Marshall Harlan II, 1999-2005 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Includes one letter from U.S. Supreme Court Justice David H. Souter, one letter from U.S. Supreme Court Justice Clarence Thomas, one letter from U.S. Supreme Court Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg, and one letter from U.S. Supreme Court Chief Justice William Rehnquist.
  - Writings - Justice Harlan paper/article, 1966-1972 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Writings - Justice Harlan paper/article, 1957-1975 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Writings - Law Clerks, 1961-1971 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    Includes one letter from U.S. Supreme Court Justice John M. Harlan.
  - Writings - Libel and the Free Press, 1963-1964 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Writings - Looking at Law School, 1989-1995 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    Includes three letters from U.S. Supreme Court Justice William J. Brennan.
  - Writings - Magna Carta - Papers for article, 1965-1966 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Writings - No Fault Insurance Act- Law review article, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Writings - None of Your Business: Government Secrecy in America., 1973-1974 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Writings - NY State Bar Committee - "We Need to Re-examine the Bar Exam", 1969-1974 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Writings - Pantheon Books - Frontiers of Civil Liberties., 1964-1972 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    Includes one letter from U.S. Supreme Court Justice Abe Fortas and one letter from U.S. Supreme Court Justice Hugo L. Black.
  - Writings - Pantheon, Post-Publication (Frontiers of Civil Liberties)., 1968-1973 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    Includes one letter from U.S. Supreme Court Justice Potter Stewart; one letter from U.S. Supreme Court Justice William O. Douglas; one letter from U.S. Supreme Court Justice William J. Brennan; one letter from U.S. Supreme Court Justice Hugo L. Black; and one letter from U.S. Supreme Court Chief Justice Earl Warren.
  - Writings - Private Schools and Civil Rights (Chicago), 1967 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Writings - Private Schools and Civil Rights (Chicago), 1967-1968 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Writings - Private Schools and Civil Rights (Chicago), 1967 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Writings - Right of Welfare, 1967-1968 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Writings - The Unpredictable Constitution, 1989-2006 (Box 16, Folder 5)